

# Software Engineer





## WHO AM I?

Hello, I am Ali Torabi, a senior software engineer. I have been working on web, desktop and console applications using various technologies for the past 7 years. I enjoy creating innovative solutions that help solve real-world problems and make a positive impact on people's lives. I am also keen on learning more about low-level programming and cloud computing.

# **SKILLS**

- Software Design
- Database Design
- · Data Structure
- · Design Patterns
- C# & .NET & SQL
- TypeScript & Vue.js
- C/C++ & Python
- Azure & AWS

## **EXPERIENCE**

## 2023 - Present Full Stack .NET Developer

**First Line Software** 

I am a software engineer working on a large E-Commerce/CMS solution named Optimizely. The main challenges are:

- · Adding complex features to project regarding the requirements.
- · Adding many useful reports for admin section.
- Adding SPA support to an existing project.

I learned the necessary skills for the project in a short time and started to write code that met the standards.

ASP.NET Core / SQL Server / Vue.js / ElasticSearch

#### 2020 - 2023

#### Full Stack .NET Developer

Gooshishop - Hasin Technology.

I was a software engineer working on a large legacy E-Commerce solution. The main challenges were:

- Maintaining project and fixing numerous bugs and issues.
- Optimizing many actions and easing the sales process.
- Choosing NopCommerce as base solution and implementing our needs in that.
- · Migrating the whole system to new product.

I'm proud to say I improved some actions up to 60% and Added so many features in years.

ASP.NET MVC / ASP.NET Core / SQL Server / PostgreSQL / ElasticSearch

#### 2020 - 2020

#### Part-Time Full Stack .NET Developer

iTelemed - Canada Telemedicine Group Inc.

I was a part-time Full Stack .NET Developer on a fully online medical solution. Main challenges were:

- Developing the project as fast as possible because of the Covid-19 situation.
- Preparing system to execute more than 100 complex requests in a minute.
- · Reaching an architecture to enable us to scale the project.

Online visiting (video chat), text chat, ticketing and managing patients were some of features built in a 3 month work.

ASP.NET Core / SQL Server / SignalR / WebRTC

#### 2019 – 2021 Full Stack .NET Developer

Algorithm Pars.

I was a senior developer working on a legacy project which was widely in use in large companies. The main challenges were:

- · Reducing the expenses of maintaining the project.
- · Creating a transition phase in order to migrate to .NET Core
- Creating and implementing a new framework to switch to ASP.NET Core.
- Reading and rewriting many parts of code and reduce line of code by 20%.

I was a key person in this project and had a good collaboration with project manager. We have improved the performance more than 15% through years.

ASP.NET Core / ASP.NET WebForms / SQL Server

### 2018 – 2019 **Software Consultant & SEO Manager**

**Sunseir Travel Agency** 

Working with my nice colleagues on a website that implements both B2B and B2C business models which handles a very high amount of request. Also improving "Sunseir" brand, advertising and SEO on aside.

ASP.NET Core / SEO Tools

#### 2017 – 2019 .**NET Developer**

Dipeh.ir

Dipeh is a website to explore about books, authors and publishers. The main goal in this project was designing a software with very specified requirements Another important goal was reaching nice performance through maximum code optimization.

ASP.NET MVC / SQL Server / Bootstrap

## 2016 – 2018 **Junior Developer & SEO Manager**

Mehr -o- Mah Travel Agency

This was my first official job as developer. It was a large-scale app with lot's of functionalities that brightened me to professional programming.

ASP.NET MVC / SQL Server / Bootstrap / SEO Tools

## **EDUCATION**

## 2016 – 2018 **Master's Degree**

Islamic Azad University, Najafabad, Iran

I focused on software engineering and software development during MS and therefore my thesis was about predicting software bugs and defects early during development

2012 – 2016 Bachelor's Degree

Zanjan University, Zanjan, Iran

## LANGUAGES

- Persian Native
- English Proficient
- · Czech Basic